Guide to the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection 2011.019
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Leila Tamari, 2014 February 23; 2011.019.078
  Crown Heights (New York, N.Y.); Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Northampton; Ethnic identity; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z New York; Haitians |z New York (State) |z New York; Israel; Morningside Heights (New York, N.Y.); Palestine; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Religious identity; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Elizabeth Velazquez, 2013 March 27; 2011.019.024
  Elizabeth Velazquez was born to a Peruvian mother and a Puerto Rican father and raised in Sullivan County, New York. Velazquez received an M.A. in painting from the State University of New York at New Paltz. She worked as an artist and art teacher in the Cypress Hills neighborhood of Brooklyn.
  In the interview, Velazquez discusses her family; Puerto Rican and Peruvian heritage; childhood experiences as a Hispanic student on the honors track in a predominantly white school district; work as an art teacher in Brooklyn, New York; perspectives on serving as a role model for students of color. Interview conducted by Nadia Williams.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Cypress Hills (New York, N.Y.); Education |z New York (State); Peru; Peruvians |z New York (State); Puerto Ricans |z New York (State); Puerto Rico; Racism in education |z New York (State); Teachers |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Whitley Watson, 2014 May 18; 2011.019.091
  Whitley Watson was born to a white American mother and an African American father in Allentown, Pennsylvania and raised in Alpharetta, Georgia. Watson received a B.F.A. in scientific illustration from the University of Georgia at Athens. She lived in New York City and worked as an artist and an administrative assistant.
  In the interview, Watson discusses her racial identity; encounters with racism; move to New York City; parents’ courtship, marriage and divorce; mother's career in the hotel industry; stepfather’s Greek heritage; and art career. Interview conducted by Jonathan Tarleton.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Bushwick (New York, N.Y.); Education |z Georgia; Flushing (New York, N.Y.); Georgia; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people
- Justice Whitaker, 2012 April 26; 2012 May 17; 2011.019.028
  Justice Whitaker was born to a white American mother and an African American father in Arroyo Grande, California. Whitaker received a B.F.A. in film and television production from New York University and studied education at Long Island University, both located in New York City. He worked as an artist and media educator in New York City.
  In the interviews, Whitaker discusses his childhood in Arroyo Grande, California; racial identity; experiences with racism, stereotyping and profiling; perspectives on activism and politics; parents' courtship, marriage, divorce, remarriages, and children; father's military service; and work as a filmmaker and educator. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
  Oral history with Justice Whitaker's partner, Alicia Piller, 2011.019.016.027.
  Arroyo Grande (Calif.); Bullying in schools |z California |z Arroyo Grande; Interfaith families; Portland (Or.); Race identity; Racial stereotyping |z California |z Arroyo Grande; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; South Africa; Teachers |z New York (State) |z New York; Thailand; Unitarianism
- Devika Wickremesinghe, 2013 October 10; 2011.019.069
  Devika Wickremesinghe was born to a white American mother and a Sri Lankan father and raised in Staten Island, New York. Wickremesinghe received a B.A. in dance and art history from Barnard College in New York City. She worked as a professional dancer.
  In the interview, Wickremesinghe discusses her racial identity; educational experiences; father's emigration from Sri Lanka; family visits to Sri Lanka; maternal grandparents' Italian heritage; relationships with siblings; and involvement in the dance community. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Oral history with Devika Wickremesinghe's sister, Neela Wickremesinghe, 2011.019.068.
  Dancers |z New York (State) |z New York; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Race identity; Racially ambiguous people; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Sri Lankan Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Neela Wickremesinghe, 2013 October 22; 2011.019.068
  Neela Wickremesinghe was born to an Italian American mother and a Sri Lankan father and raised in Staten Island, New York. Wickremesinghe received a B.A. in architecture and urbanism from Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts and an M.S. in historic preservation from Columbia University in New York City. She worked as an architecture conservator in New York City and Minneapolis, Minnesota.
  In the interview, Wickremesinghe discusses her Italian, Sinhalese, and Dutch heritage; racial identity; family visits to Sri Lanka; educational experiences; career in architecture; and impressions of crime and demographics in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Oral history with Neela Wickremesinghe's sister, Devika Wickremesinghe, 2011.019.069.
  Architecture |x Conservation and restoration; Italian Americans |z New York (State) |z Staten Island; Minneapolis (Minn.); Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Sinhalese (Sri Lankan people); Sri Lanka; Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)
- Teresa Wiltz, 2014 May 9; 2011.019.087
  Teresa Wiltz was born to African American parents in Washington, D.C. She was raised in Staten Island, New York and Atlanta, Georgia. Wiltz received a B.A. in playwriting from Dartmouth College in Hanover, New Hampshire and worked as a journalist for the Washington Post and Chicago Tribune.
  In the interview, Wiltz discusses her African, Creole, European, and Native American ancestry; parents' experiences growing up during segregation in the South; and connections to New Orleans, Louisiana, where her father was raised. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.
  African Americans |z Georgia |z Atlanta; African Americans |z New York (State) |z Staten Island; Atlanta (Ga.); Bullying in schools |z Georgia |z Atlanta; Bullying in schools |z New York (State) |z Staten Island; Education |z Georgia |z Atlanta; New Orleans (La.); Passing (Identity); Race identity; Racially ambiguous people; Racially mixed people; Segregation |z United States; Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)
- Manyi Wong, 2014 January 27; 2011.019.073
  Manyi Wong was born to Chinese parents in Hong Kong and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Wong received a B.F.A. in art photography from Syracuse University in New York and an M.S. in organizational change management from the New School in New York City. She worked as the executive director at the Park Slope Child Care Collective in Brooklyn, New York.
  In the interview, Wong discusses her family’s immigration experiences in Hong Kong and the United States; maternal grandparents' marriage and separation; experiences with racial tension in Syracuse, New York; photography career; marriage to her Indian American husband; and experiences naming and raising their daughter. Interview conducted by Sady Sullivan.
  Bensonhurst (New York, N.Y.); Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Interethnic marriage; Marriage customs and rites |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Parenthood; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Clare Workneh and Fikre Workneh, 2012 February 10; 2011.019.018.020
  Clare Workneh was born to white American Catholic parents in Brooklyn, New York and raised in Floral Park, New York. Upon graduation from Our Lady of Mercy High School, Clare became a nun with the Maryknoll Sisters in Ossining, New York. She left the order after eight years and worked for the United Methodist Board of Social Ministries.
  Fikre Workneh was born to Ethiopian parents and raised in Gojjam, Ethiopia. He was a minister in the Ethiopian Orthodox Church and served as a missionary in the Caribbean before immigrating to the United States. He attended the Silberman School of Social Work at Hunter College in New York City and worked for the National Institute of Mental Health.
  In the interviews, Clare and Fikre and discuss their religious backgrounds; courtship, wedding, and marriage; encounters with racism and prejudice; and their children. Fikre also discusses Ethiopia's role in the Arab-Israeli conflict. Interviews conducted by Liza Zapol.
  Arab-Israeli conflict; Catholicism; Discrimination in housing |z New York (State) |z New York; Ethiopia; Ethiopian Orthodox Church; Ethiopians |z New York (State) |z New York; Interfaith marriage; Racially mixed families; Religious institutions |z New York (State) |z New York; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Geo Wyeth, 2014 June 4; 2011.019.098
  Geographical note
  Geo Wyeth was born to an African American mother and a white American father in New York City. He was raised in the Hell's Kitchen neighborhood of Manhattan and Montclair, New Jersey. Wyeth received a B.A. in American studies from Yale University in New Haven, Connecticut. Following graduation, he moved to the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked at Apple, Inc. and as a freelance writer, musician, and artist.
  In the interview, Wyeth discusses his racial and gender identities; incidents of racism and bullying in the Hell's Kitchen neighborhood of Manhattan and Montclair, New Jersey; relationship to the artistic community; and his mother's experiences growing up in Washington, D.C. as schools were desegregated. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.
  Artists |z New York (State) |z New York; Bullying in schools |z New Jersey |z Montclair; Bullying in schools |z New York (State) |z New York; Crime |z New York (State) |z New York; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Gender identity; Hell's Kitchen (New York, N.Y.); Montclair (N.J.); Queer identity; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people
- Bette Yee, 2012 February 26; 2011.019.021
  Bette Yee was born to Chinese parents in Boston, Massachusetts and raised in Hooksett, New Hampshire. Yee received a B.A. in sociology and math from the University of New Hampshire. She worked in the finance industry in New York City and volunteered with the Organization of Asian Women.
  In the interview, Yee discusses cultural values and gender roles in her family; experiences with bullying in Hooksett, New Hampshire; courtship with her first husband, a white American with French-Canadian heritage, who served in the Vietnam War; and involvement in New York City's Asian community. Interview conducted by Cynthia Lee.
  Oral history interview with Bette Yee's son, Jonathan Blazon, 2011.019.022.
  Bullying in schools |z New Hampshire |z Hooksett; Catholics |z New Hampshire; Chinese Americans |z New Hampshire; Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Community organizing |z New York (State) |z New York; Cooking |x Social aspects; Education |z New Hampshire; New Hampshire; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Prospect Heights (New York, N.Y.); Racially mixed families; Sex role